Finding Aid for the Recordings of Creative Associates Recitals, 1964-1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Recordings of Creative Associates Recitals, 1964-1980
Mus. Arc. 63
State University of New York at Buffalo. Center of the Creative and Performing Arts
12.5 linear feet (172 reel to reel tapes in 15 cartons, 324 audio cassettes in 6 boxes, 1 external hard drive)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains 172 original reel to reel tape recordings of 113 recitals containing approximately 613 works. The works range from the Renaissance to music created for the concerts, even improvised at the events. The reels are accompanied by audio cassette recordings created as service copies and a hard drive containing digitally reformatted preservation and access files.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of State University of New York at Buffalo Music Department.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
The first access service copies for the reel to reel tapes were provided by copying content onto audio cassettes sometime around 1978-1980. The contents were transferred as one musical work per one cassette side. The cassettes were numbered and inventoried. The cassettes have been retained and shelved with the collection as backup copies.
The reel to reel tapes were digitized in 2018 by Northeast Document Conservation Center and the reformatted contents were delivered on a single external hard drive. Copies were transferred to a server for backup and storage. Preservation Broadcast Wave Format files matching the original reels of tape (one digital file per face of a reel) were created at 96 kHz, 24-bit resolution. Due to the discrete musical works on the tapes, production master files were then created to match the musical content, one file per work at the same resolution as the preservation masters. Access service copies matching the content of the Production master files were created as MP3 format files at 44.1 kHz, 192kbps resolution.
Digital files were named according to the following convention, all using ubmu0063 to represent the archival collection number:
Preservation file: ubmu0063_001am.wav with 001 representing the tape number and am representing Archival master
Production master file: ubmu0063_001_01am.wav with 001 representing the tape number, _01 representing the work number, and pm representing Production master
Access service file: ubmu0063_001_01sc.mp3 with 001 representing the tape number, _01 representing the work number, and pm representing Service copy
Historical Note
The Creative Associates Recitals were a product of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, established to give young professional performers and composers the opportunity to focus on the production of new music. Lukas Foss, Music Director for the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra 1963-1971, approached Gordon Smith, director of the Albright-Knox Art Gallery 1955-1973, to develop ideas for a Center of New Music in Buffalo. In discussions with Allan Sapp, Director of the University at Buffalo Music Department, and the Rockefeller Foundation, a proposal was submitted to the Foundation for the development of the Center. Modeled after the Evenings-on-the-Roof concert series in Los Angeles, the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts was “founded on notions of providing performing ensembles, of making definitive renditions of new and complicated music feasible, of bringing composers and performers into the closest working relationships, of developing a corpus of recordings and privately-held scores, of establishing a central locus for the study of new techniques of composition notation and performance practice.” The proposal was accepted and the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts began operation in 1964.
Directors of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts included the founders, Lukas Foss and Allan Sapp, who acted as Co-Directors from 1964-68; Lejaren Hiller, Co-Director with Lukas Foss from 1968-74; Jan Williams, Co-Director with Renée Levine from 1974-76; Renée Levine, Center Coordinator from 1964-74 and Co-Director from 1974-78; and Morton Feldman, Music Director from 1976-1980. Performers and composers selected to be fellows at the Center were given the title of Creative Associate.
There were two main concert series produced by the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts: Evenings for New Music concerts and Creative Associate Recitals. Evenings for New Music concerts were performed in Buffalo and also performed, often with changes in programs, at various other venues. Creative Associates Recitals were performed within Buffalo, most often on the campus of the University at Buffalo. The Recitals were the programmed by the Creative Associates themselves as supplements to the Evenings for New Music concerts. The Associates were free to program whatever works they wished. As a result, the programs include a repertoire ranging from the Renaissance through new music composed expressly for the recitals.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains recordings of approximately 613 works performed on 113 of the 127 recitals presented 1964-1980 by the Creative Associates of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts. A complete listing of all the concerts, including works and concerts not recorded, can be seen in the original inventory online.
The music of more than 200 composers is represented in the collection. Due to the eclectic nature of the progamming, a wide range of composers is included, from the 14th to 20th centuries. Music from the 20th century spans a diverse spectrum of musical styles from more traditional to avant garde. Composers whose works were performed include Crumb, Berio, Wuorinen, Carter, Copland, Bussotti, Scelsi, Feldman, Cage, as well as lesser-known figures whose representation here may be rare. Performers included some of the most skilled practicioners of contemporary music. There are also many instances of composers either performing or directing performances of their own works.
Of the new music performed, there are works that were presented in what amounted to draft versions. Upon examination, some works no longer appear on the works lists of their composers. As a result, these recordings could represent the only surviving documentation of some of the compositions performed. Close to 20 premieres were performed. Some recordings require more research to fully describe due the practice of performing multiple works simultaneously or other factors that make clear definition challenging.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series according to format.
I. Reel to reel tapes
II. Cassettes
III. External hard drive
Container List
- Reel to reel tapes, 1964-1980, I.; Reel 1-Reel 172
  This series contains all the 172 original reel to reel recordings.
  Chronologically arranged by concert and then by order on the program. It is important to note that the 128 known recitals were sequentially numbered in chronological order based on supplementary documentation such as concert programs. There are gaps in the sequence below for the fifteen concerts not recorded. However, the reels were sequentially numbered based on what was in hand. As a result, their numbering does not correlate to the recital numbering. Work numbering was based on where the work is on a tape, not where it may have been stated on a printed program. There are many cases where programs were changed at the time of performance. The tapes have been grouped and listed according to the concerts. Original concert programs are included with most of the tapes. These often contain markings by the recording engineers regarding program order and technical issues of the recording such as tape speed or exceptional conditions.
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 1, November 13, 1964, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 1, Reel 001-002)
    Work number: ubmu0063_001_01
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
    Drei Romanzen, op. 94
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; George Crumb, piano
    Duration: 12:28
    Cassette backup: CA 001
    Work number: ubmu0063_001_02
    Liederkreis, op. 39
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; George Crumb, piano
    Duration: 28:02
    Cassette backup: CA 002
    Work number: ubmu0063_002_01
    Berg, Alban, 1885-1935
    Vier Lieder, op. 2
    Duration: 9:30
    Cassette backup: CA 003
    Work number: ubmu0063_002_02
    Vier Stucke fur Klarinette und Klavier, op. 5
    Duration: 10:47
    Cassette backup: CA 004
    Work number: ubmu0063_002_03
    Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828
    Die Verschworenen, D. 787. Romanze
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; George Crumb, piano
    Duration: 16:32
    Cassette backup: CA 005
    Work number: ubmu0063_002_04
    Der Hirt auf dem Felsen, op. posth. 129
    Duration: 5:52
    Cassette backup: CA 006
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 2, December 19, 1964, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 1, Reel 003-004)
    Work number: ubmu0063_003_01
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
    Overture, clarinets, 2 horns, D major
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, clarinet; Stephen Seiffert, horn
    Duration: 12:39
    Cassette backup: CA 007
    Work number: ubmu0063_003_02
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949
    Till Eulenspiegel, arranged
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Beatrice Wernick, bassoon; Stephen Seiffert, horn; Charles Joseph, violin; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Cassette backup: CA 008
    Work number: ubmu0063_004_01
    Walton, William, 1902-1983
    Facade, reciter, chamber ensemble
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, Laurence Bogue, reciters; Karl Kraber, flute, piccolo; Sherman Friedland, clarinet, bass clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, alto saxophone; (not named), trumpet; Jan Williams, percussion, Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 43:13
    Cassette backup: CA 009
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 3, February 3, 1965, 3 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 1, Reel 005-007)
    Work number: ubmu0063_005_01
    Shapey, Ralph, 1921-2002
    Evocation (1959)
    Performers: Paul Zukofsky, violin; George Crumb, piano; John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 15:45
    Cassette backup: CA 010
    Work number: ubmu0063_005_02
    Martino, Donald, 1931-2005
    Fantasy-variations (1962)
    Performers: Paul Zukofsky, violin
    Duration: 11:59
    Cassette backup: CA 011
    Work number: ubmu0063_005_03
    Crumb, George
    Nocturnes, violin, piano
    Performers: Paul Zukofsky, violin; George Crumb, piano
    Duration: 11:26
    Cassette backup: CA 012
    Note: Premiere performance.
    Work number: ubmu0063_006_01
    Haubenstock-Ramati, Roman
    Liaisons (1961)
    Performers: John Bergamo, vibraphone
    Duration: 7:21
    Cassette backup: CA 013
    Work number: ubmu0063_006_02
    Berger, Arthur, 1912-2003
    Duo no. 2 (1950)
    Duration: 14:33
    Cassette backup: CA 014
    Work number: ubmu0063_007_01
    Schuller, Gunther
    Trio (1957)
    Duration: 19:30
    Cassette backup: CA 015
    Work number: ubmu0063_007_02
    Ives, Charles, 1874-1954
    Sonata, violin, piano, no. 2. In the barn
    Duration: 7:58
    Cassette backup: CA 016
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 4, February 15, 1965, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 1, Reel 008-009)
    Work number: ubmu0063_008_01
    Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990
    As it fell upon a day (1923)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet
    Duration: 6:47
    Cassette backup: CA 019
    Work number: ubmu0063_008_02
    Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958
    Blake Songs
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Sherman Friedland, clarinet
    Duration: 10:20
    Cassette backup: CA 020
    Work number: ubmu0063_008_03
    Webern, Anton, 1883-1945
    Funf Canons, op. 16
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, bass clarinet
    Duration: 4:47
    Cassette backup: CA 021
    Work number: ubmu0063_008_04
    Sahl, Michael, 1934-
    Foundation Song (1965)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Michael Sahl, piano
    Duration: 7:38
    Cassette backup: CA 022
    Work number: ubmu0063_009_01
    Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
    Trio, piano, flute, violoncello, H. XV:15, G major
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Michael Sahl, piano; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 17:41
    Cassette backup: CA 017
    Work number: ubmu0063_009_02
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
    Trio, piano, clarinet, violoncello, op. 11, B-flat major
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Michael Sahl, piano
    Duration: 22:34
    Cassette backup: CA 018
    Note: Check contents: tape container states 2 of 2 but inserted program indicates contents from 1st half of concert. Check contents against program to see if the programs in Tapes 8 and 9 are reversed.
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 5, March 31, 1965, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 1, Reel 010-011)
    Work number: ubmu0063_010_01
    Bononcini, Giovanni, 1670-1747
    Mario Fuggitivo. Dalinda's Aria
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 3:24
    Cassette backup: CA 023
    Work number: ubmu0063_010_02
    Nel dolce dell'oblio (cantata)
    Duration: 7:39
    Cassette backup: CA 024
    Work number: ubmu0063_010_03
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
    Cantata no. 100: Was Gott tut, das ist wohlgetan. Excerpt
    Duration: 5:34
    Cassette backup: CA 025
    Work number: ubmu0063_010_04
    Cantata no. 211: Kaffee-Kantate. Ei, wie schmeckt der Kaffe susse
    Duration: 5:00
    Cassette backup: CA 026
    Work number: ubmu0063_010_05
    Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel, 1714-1788
    Sonata, flute, continuo, W. 124, E minor
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 7:08
    Cassette backup: CA 027
    Work number: ubmu0063_010_06
    Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856
    Bravura Variations
    Duration: 6:42
    Cassette backup: CA 028
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_01
    Mortari, Virgilio, 1902-1993
    Vocalise (1943)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute
    Duration: 3:15
    Cassette backup: CA 029
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_02
    Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937
    Deux Poems de Ronsard (1924)
    Duration: 8:22
    Cassette backup: CA 030
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_03
    Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937
    Sheherazade. La flute enchantee
    Duration: 4:03
    Cassette backup: CA 031
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_04
    Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918
    Syrinx (1913)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute
    Duration: 2:55
    Cassette backup: CA 032
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_05
    Varèse, Edgard, 1883-1965
    Density 21.5 (1935)
    Duration: 3:48
    Cassette backup: CA 033
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_06
    Arrigo, Girolamo
    Quattro Episodi (1963)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Karl Kraber, flutes
    Duration: 5:56
    Cassette backup: CA 034
    Work number: ubmu0063_011_07
    Ravel, Maurice
    Sheherazade. La flute enchantee (encore)
    Duration: 3:44
    Cassette backup: NA
    Note: Performed as encore.
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 6, April 29, 1965, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 1, Reel 012-013)
    Work number: ubmu0063_012_01
    Philidor, André, circa 1647-1730
    Military Music for two pairs of timpani (circa 1780)
    Performers: Jan Williams, John Bergamo, timpani
    Duration: 3:29
    Cassette backup: CA 035
    Work number: ubmu0063_012_02
    Bussotti, Sylvano
    Coeur pour Batteur (1959)
    Performers: John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 11:32
    Cassette backup: CA 036
    Work number: ubmu0063_012_03
    Carter, Elliott, 1908-
    Eight pieces for 4 timpani. V, II, I
    Performers: Jan Williams, timpani
    Duration: 12:20
    Cassette backup: CA 037
    Work number: ubmu0063_013_01
    Rosen, Jerome, 1921-2011
    Elegy for solo percussion
    Performers: Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 9:04
    Cassette backup: CA 038
    Work number: ubmu0063_013_02
    Fuller, Ramon Conrad, 1930-
    Music for Two Channel Tape and Two percussionists (1964)
    Performers: John Bergamo, Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 9:45
    Cassette backup: CA 039
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 7, October 10, 1965, 5 7-inch reels; ½-track mono and stereo, 15 ips (Box 1, Reel 014-018)
    Work number: ubmu0063_014_01
    Cornysh, William, d. 1523
    Robyn, gentil robyn
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Duration: 3:04
    Cassette backup: CA 040
    Work number: ubmu0063_014_02
    Hilton, John, d. ca. 1608
    Fantasia a tre
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; John Bergamo, marimba; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Duration: 2:29
    Cassette backup: CA 041
    Work number: ubmu0063_014_03
    Dowland, John
    Lowest trees have tops
    Duration: 2:41
    Cassette backup: CA 042
    Note: Not included in original inventory - assigned cassette number for ordering.
    Work number: ubmu0063_014_04
    Rossi, Salomone, fl. 1587-1628
    Bar'chu
    Duration: 1:58
    Cassette backup: CA 043
    Work number: ubmu0063_014_05
    Jeffreys, George, ca. 1610-1685
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; John Bergamo, vibraphone; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Duration: 3:25
    Cassette backup: CA 044
    Work number: ubmu0063_014_06
    Jones, Robert, fl. 1520-1534
    In Sherwood lived stout Robin
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute, piccolo; John Bergamo, marimba; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Duration: 2:33
    Cassette backup: CA 045
    Work number: ubmu0063_015_01
    Sensitivo
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 6:16
    Cassette backup: CA 046
    Work number: ubmu0063_015_02
    Lettura di Braibanti
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano
    Duration: 4:57
    Cassette backup: CA 046a
    Work number: ubmu0063_016_01
    Cage, John
    Percussion Solo
    Duration: 13:26
    Cassette backup: CA 048
    Work number: ubmu0063_017_01
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
    Acht Stücke fur Flöte allein (1927)
    Duration: 7:15
    Cassette backup: CA 049
    Work number: ubmu0063_017_02
    In My Craft or Sullen Art
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; John Bergamo, percussion; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Duration: 6:51
    Cassette backup: CA 050
    Work number: ubmu0063_018_01
    Atlas Eclipticalis with Solo for voice 1
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; John Bergamo, percussion; Buell Neidlinger, double bass
    Cassette backup: CA 051
    Work number: ubmu0063_018_02
    Es ist genug, BWV Anh. 157
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; John Bergamo, percussion
    Cassette backup: CA 052
    Work number: ubmu0063_018_03
    It was a lover and his lass
    Duration: 2:00
    Cassette backup: CA 052a
    Note: Not on printed program. Not included in original inventory - assigned cassette number for ordering.
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 8, October 13, 1965, 2 10-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 3, Reel 019-020)
    Work number: ubmu0063_019_01
    Gillespie, Dizzy, 1917-1993
    Woody 'n You
    Performers: Andrew White, alto saxophone; Buell Neidlinger, double bass; John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 29:07
    Cassette backup: CA 053
    Work number: ubmu0063_019_02
    White, Andrew, 1942-
    Milestone II
    Duration: 14:54
    Cassette backup: CA 054
    Work number: ubmu0063_020_01-03
    Taylor, Cecil, 1919-
    Money, Metal Vistas and the Catalyst. Flowers pluck themselves
    Performers: Buell Neidlinger, double bass; Andrew White III, saxophone; John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 49:36
    Cassette backup: CA 055-057
    Note: With Ancient Indian: Flowers Pluck Themselves -- Sonny Criss: Impressions.
    Note: The divisions between pieces are not clear; production master and service copy are of entire performance undivided.
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 9, October 27, 1965, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 2, Reel 021-022)
    Work number: ubmu0063_021_01
    Five Songs: Lied auf Suleika; Liebeslied; Der Nussbaum; Im Walde; Der Hidalgo
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Michael Sahl, piano
    Duration: 11:14
    Cassette backup: CA 058
    Work number: ubmu0063_021_02
    Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951
    Gedichte aus Das Buch der hangenden Garten. III, VIII, XV
    Duration: 8:35
    Cassette backup: CA 059
    Work number: ubmu0063_021_03-08
    Six songs: Ann Street; Things our fathers loved; Cage; Housatonic at Stockbridge; Slide show; Vita
    Duration: 10:01
    Cassette backup: CA 060-065
    Work number: ubmu0063_022_01
    Biel, Michael von
    For piano No. III
    Performers: Michael von Biel, Michael Sahl, pianos
    Duration: 15:41
    Cassette backup: CA 067
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 11, January 21, 1966, 2 7-inch reels (Box 2) and 1 10-inch reel (Box 3); ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 2-3, Reel 023-025)
    Work number: ubmu0063_023_01
    Ichiyanagi, Toshi
    Sapporo
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Vinko Globokar, trombone; Dagmar von Biel, Violin; Michael von Biel, violoncello; Buell Neidlinger, double bass; Michael Sahl, David Tudor, pianos
    Duration: 24:41
    Cassette backup: CA 073
    Work number: ubmu0063_024_01
    Solos (2) for voice II, electronic version
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; David Tudor, piano
    Duration: 14:11
    Cassette backup: CA 074
    Work number: ubmu0063_025_01
    Atlas Eclipticalis (1961)
    Performers: John Bergamo, Jan Williams, timpani; John Hathaway, Michael Horwood, Buell Neidlinger, Michael Sahl, James Santella, Mark Schneider, percussion
    Duration: 1:07:37
    Cassette backup: CA 075
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 13, April 6, 1966, 2 7-inch reels; ½-track mono, 7.5 ips (Box 2, Reel 026-027)
    Work number: ubmu0063_026_01
    Colgrass, Michael
    Percussion Music (1953)
    Performers: Robert McFadden, James Santella, William Thiele, Ralph Wynn, percussion
    Cassette backup: CA 082
    Work number: ubmu0063_026_02
    Feldman, Morton
    King of Denmark (1964)
    Cassette backup: CA 083
    Work number: ubmu0063_026_03
    Harrison, Lou
    Canticle No. 3
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Robert McFadden, John Hathaway, Philip Huffsmith, James Santella, William Thiele, Ralph Wynn, percussion
    Duration: 18:56
    Cassette backup: CA 084
    Note: Engineer's note: Fade around 8:15
    Work number: ubmu0063_027_01
    Sahl, Michael
    Suggestions to the Drummer (1966)
    Duration: 6:50
    Cassette backup: CA 085
    Work number: ubmu0063_027_02
    Bergamo, John J.
    Bells, Flowers and … (1966)
    Performers: John Bergamo, vibraphone, piano; Buell Neidlinger, double bass, piano
    Duration: 11:54
    Cassette backup: CA 086
    Work number: ubmu0063_027_03
    Varèse, Edgar
    Ionisation (1931)
    Performers: John Bergamo, Jan Williams, Robert McFadden, John Hathaway, Philip Huffsmith, James Santella, William Thiele, Ralph Wynn, Doug Carroll, Joseph Guarnieri, Michael Horwood, Buell Neidlinger, and Michael Sahl, percussion
    Duration: 6:28
    Cassette backup: CA 087
    Work number: ubmu0063_027_04
    Ionisation (repeat performance)
    Duration: 7:25
    Cassette backup: CA 087a